Dell H. Hymes Papers 1947-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.55
American Philosophical Society
Dell H. Hymes Papers
1947-1992
Mss.Ms.Coll.55
American Philosophical Society
70.0 Linear feet
Dell Hymes' doctoral research on Kathlamet Chinook (Indiana University, 1955) grew into a lifelong interest in the relationship between ethnography and linguistics. Following academic appointments at Harvard University (1955-1960) and the University of California, Berkley (1960-1965), Hymes joined the Department of Anthropology at the University of Pennsylvania in 1965. During twenty-two years tenure at Penn he was a professor of folklore, linguistics, sociology and education. In 1975, he was promoted to Dean of the Graduate School of Education (1975-1987). A principal proponent of the emergent field of sociolinguistics, his most influential works include Reinventing Anthropology and Language in Culture and Society. The Hymes papers cover all aspects of Dell Hymes' professional life, though concentrated on his years at the University of Pennsylvania, his presidencies of the American Association of Anthropology and the Linguistic Society of America, and his editorship of the journal Language in Society. Of particular interest is his rich correspondence with colleagues and students on linguistic issues. The papers reflect Hymes' interests in the history of linguistics and anthropology, Native American languages, and his comparative ethnographies of communication.
Hymes, Dell H.
Bibliography
Gumperz, John Joseph and Dell H. Hymes, joint eds. The Ethnography of Communication (Washington: American Anthropological Association, 1964) Call no. 572.05 Am3 v.66, no.6
Hymes, Dell H. Alfred Louis Kroeber (Baltimore, 1961). Call no. 405 L26 v.37
Hymes, Dell H. and John Fought. American Structuralism (The Hague: Mouton, 1981) Call no. 409 H99a
Hymes, Dell H. Essays in the History of Linguistic Anthropology (Philadelphia: John Benjamins Publishing Co., 1983) Call no. 410.9 H99p
Hymes, Dell H. In Vain I Tried to Tell You: Essays in Native American ethnopoetics (Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 1981) Call no. 897 H99i
Hymes, Dell H., ed. Language in Culture and Society: A Reader in Linguistics and Anthropology (New York: Harper & Row, 1964) Call no. 408 H99L
Hymes, Dell H. The Language of the Kathlamet Chinook (Doctoral dissertation, 1955) Call no. 497.4 H99 (manuscript)
Hymes, Dell H. Lexicostatistics and Glottochronology in the Nineteenth Century (The Hague: Mouton, 1973) Call no. 400 Pam. no.44
Hymes, Dell H. Lexicostatistics So Far (Chicago, 1960) Call no. 572.05 C93 v.1, no.1
Hymes, Dell H. Modjeska on Sapir and Croce: A Comment (Washington, 1969) Call no. 572.05 Am3 v.71, no.3
Hymes, Dell H., ed. Reinventing Anthropology (New York: Random House, 1972) Call no. 572.07 H99r
Hymes, Dell H. Some North Pacific Poems: A Problem in Anthropological Philology (Menasha, 1965) Call no. 572.05 Am3 v.67, no.2
Hymes, Dell H. Toward a History of Linguistic Anthropology (Berkley, 1962) Call no. 572.09 C76p no.13
Voeglin, C.F. (Charles Frederick) and Dell H. Hymes. A Sample of North American Indian Dictionaries with Reference to Acculturation (Philadelphia: American Philosophical Society, 1953) Call no. 506.73 Am4p v.97
African American History Note
The following materials may be of interest to scholars of African American history:
Baugh, John. Manuscript Materials. n.d. 5 folders (Approximately 105 pages).
Typed materials of Baugh, a former student of Hymes, concerning African American language dialects--standard African American English and African American vernacular English. Includes several research proposals: " Black English Style Shifting," " Formal Refinement of the Notion for Rules within the Labovian Variable Paradigm," " Linguistic Characteristics of Afro-American Ethnicity Detection: Targets for the Acquisition of Standard English," " The Social Stratification of Black and Hispanic English;" and, a survey which was published in the Annual Review of Anthropology (1983): " A survey of Afro-American English."
Related Archival Materials note
Dell H. Hymes appears as correspondent in several APS collections, including the papers of Anthony Wallace (Ms. Coll. 64a), Floyd Lounsbury (Ms. Coll. 95), and Ward Goodenough (Ms. Coll. 120).
In the 1980s, Hymes donated to the APS the Walter Dyk Collection (497.3 H998m) which includes the grammar and verbs of Wishram and the Yana vocabulary and notes of Alfred Lewis Kroeber (497.3 B63c H6.6).
Other related collections include the C. F. Voegelin Papers (Ms. Coll. 68), the Harry Hoijer Collection (497.3 H68), and the Mary Rosamond Haas Papers (Ms. Coll. 94).
APS also possesses: a copy of Hymes' dissertation at Indiana University (1955), The Language of the Kathlamet Chinook (497.4 H99); and the manuscript of a work by Hymes entitled Reading Takelma texts: Frances Johnson's "Coyote and Frog" (897.974 H99r).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Dell H. Hymes, 1987, 1993.
Scope and Contents note
The Hymes' papers reflect linguistic anthropology's shift to sociolinguistics during the 1960s to 1980s. While the papers contain Hymes' study of the Chinookan language, their primary focus is the concept of language as social phenomenon. Within the Series I and II, he urges the need for comparative studies that view speech as part of a broader cultural system of communicative action. The correspondence is diverse, including fellow anthropologists plus social scientists, poets, educators, communicators and literary scholars.
The collection also mirrors Hymes' interests in the problems of language reconstruction and the history of linguistics and of anthropology. The largest series, Series V, contains accepted and rejected works for the journal Language in Society. The papers are a rich resource in social causes of the 1960s and 1970s, including the Vietnam peace movement, the ethical issues for anthropologists in Thailand, and the blacklisting of scientists for their political actions.
Throughout the collection, Hymes' social conscience is ever present. It resounds with the changes he championed within his discipline and within the academic community.
The papers (140 boxes; 70 linear feet) are divided into five series:
Series I. Correspondence 1951 - 1987 17 linear feet
Series II. Conferences and Committees 1955-1987 11 linear feet
Series III. Works by Hymes 1947-1987 3 linear feet
Series IV. Works by Others 1955-1987 2 linear feet
Series V. Language in Society 1968-1992 37 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
Dell Hathaway Hymes, an anthropologist, linguist, and educator, is best known for his studies of the language and culture of Native Americans at the Warm Springs reservation in Central Oregon. He was born in Portland, Oregon on 7 June 1927, the son of Howard Hathaway and Dorothy (Bowman) Hymes. After two years of military service (1945-1947), Hymes received his undergraduate degree from Reed College (1950) and went on to study linguistic anthropology under Carl Voegelin at Indiana University. Thus was the beginning of his lifelong linguistic study of the Wasco tribe. His dissertation, The Language of Kathlamet Chinook (1955), was drawn from texts recorded and published by Franz Boas. After his marriage to Virginia Margaret Dosch in 1954, Hymes continued his post-graduate work with Harry Hoijer at UCLA. Between 1955-1960, he taught social anthropology at Harvard University and then went on to teach anthropology at the University of California, Berkeley (1960-1965).
Hymes' long association with the University of Pennsylvania began in 1965 as a professor of anthropology. Over his twenty-two year tenure at Penn he was a professor of folklore, linguistics, sociology, and education with a promotion to Dean of the Graduate School of Education (1975-1987). He also served on various committees at Penn including the Committee on problems of War and Peace, the Christian Association, the Committee on Language, Culture and Society, and the Haney Foundation Editorial Committee.
Hymes' first published work was in historical linguistics, Language in Culture and Society (1964). He believed that those who studied both linguistics and anthropology need to develop an opinion on the relation of language to culture. All of Hymes' works has been a response to finding a relationship between the two. He argues that linguistics should be based on a conception of language as social phenomena. As a result of this perspective, Hymes became a principal proponent of the emergent field of sociolinguistics. His other edited works include The Use of Computers in Anthropology (1965), Studies in Southwestern Ethnolinguistics (1967), Pidginization and Creolization of Languages (1971), Reinventing Anthropology (1972). Some later published works include Foundations of Sociolinguistics (1974), Language in Education: ethnolinguistic essays (1980), In Vain I Tried to Tell You: essays in Native American ethnopoetics (1981), American Structuralism (with John Fought, 1981). He returned to his historical perspective with the work Essays in the History of Linguistic Anthropology in 1983. With John Gumperz, he edited Directions in Sociolinguistics: the enthnography of communication (1986) that views speech as a part of a broader cultural system of communication action.
Hymes was also very active in professional organizations. With his strong interest in combating elitism and to ensure that anthropologists maintain knowledge of other societal disciplines, he has served on many executive boards. He has had a career-long association with the Social Science Research Council as one of the founding members of the Committee on Sociolinguistics (1963-1980). He served as president of the American Folklore Society (1973-1974), the Linguistic Society of America (1982), the American Anthropological Association (1983), and the American Association of Applied Linguistics (1986).
In 1972, Hymes founded the journal Language in Society and served as its primary editor until 1992. Other associate editor services include work with The Journal of the History of the Behavioral Sciences (1966-1993), American Journal of Sociology (1977-1980), Journal of Pragmatics (1977-), and Theory and Society (1976-1996). In 1987, Hymes accepted the position of professor of Anthropology and English at the University of Virginia and became emeritus in 2000. He continues to work on Native American languages focusing on the analysis of oral narratives in verse. Dr. Hymes and his wife, Virginia, presently reside in Charlottesville, Virginia. They are the parents of Robert Paul (adopted), Alison Bowman, Kenneth Dell and Vicki (stepchild).
Aberle, David F., 1918-; American Academy of Arts and Sciences.; American Anthropological Association.; American Association of Applied Linguistics; American Folklore Society.; Austerlitz, Robert, 1923-1994; Basso, Keith, 1940-; Baugh, John; Bauman, Richard; Ben-Amos, Dan; Bennett, Ruth S.; Bernstein, Basil; Bright, William, 1928-2006; Burke, Kenneth,1897-1993; Cambridge University Press; Cazden, Courtney, 1925-; Chomsky, Noam; Cowgill, George L.; Diamond, Stanley; Douglas, Mary, 1921-; Dozier, Edward, 1916-1971; Driver, Harold; Duranti, Alessandro, 1950-; Durbin, Marshall; Dyk, Walter, 1899-1972; Embree, Lester; Fought, John.; Frake, Charles O.; French, David H.; Friedrich, Paul, 1927-; Fromm, Erich,1900-1980; Goffman, Erving; Goodenough, Ward H., 1919-; Gregorian, Vartan, 1934-; Grimshaw, Allen D.; Gumperz, John,1922-; Haas, Mary R., (Mary Rosamond), 1910-1996; Harris, Zellig S., (Zellig Sabbettai), 1909-; Harris, Marvin, 1927-2001; Hiz, Henry T.; Hockett, Charles, 1916-; Hoenigswald, Henry M., 1915-2003; Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976; Irvine, Judith.; Jacobs, Melville, 1902-1971; Jakobson, Roman, 1896-1982; Koerner, E.F. Konrad,; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Kroeber, Theodora; Labov, William, 1927-; Lévi-Strauss, Claude; Linguistic Society of America.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Martin, Paul S., 1899-1974; McDermott, Ray; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Mintz, Sidney Wilfred, 1922-; Mouton Publishers; Nader, Laura, 1930-; Neustupny, Jiri; Nida, Eugene A.; Philips, Susan U.; Ramsey, Jarold, 1937-; Rigsby, Bruce Joseph, 1937-; Sankoff, Gillian; Sapir, J. David; Sapir, Philip; Schneider, David M., 1918-1995; Scholte, Bob, 1902-1983; Sebeok, Thomas A., 1920-2001; Sherzer, Joel.; Shuy, Roger W.; Silverstein, Michael; Snyder, Gary, 1930-; Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations .; Stocking, George W., 1928-; Sturtevant, William C.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967; Szwed, John F.; Tax, Sol, 1907-1995; Tedlock, Dennis, 1939-; Toelken, Barre, 1935-; University of Pennsylvania Press; University of Pennsylvania-Annenberg School of Communication; University of Pennsylvania-Department of Anthropology; University of Pennsylvania-Department of Folklore & Folklife; University of Pennsylvania-Department of Linguistics; University of Pennsylvania-Department of Sociology; University of Pennsylvania-Graduate School of Education; University of Pennsylvania.; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-; Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research.; Worth, Sol, 1922-1977; Anthropologists -- United States.; Anthropology, ethnography, fieldwork; Cathlamet dialect; Chinookan languages; Creole dialects; Indians of North America--Ethnology; Indians of North America--Languages; Indians of North America--Northwest Coast; Indians of North America--Oregon; Language in Society; Language, linguistics; Languages, Mixed; Linguistics; Pidgin languages; Race, race relations, racism; Shahaptian languages
- Series I. Correspondence, 1951-1987; 17 lin. feet (Box 1-32)
  Scope and Contents note
  Ingoing and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams and postcards generated during Hymes' career, some personal, but primarily professional. This series often contains scholarly works by the correspondent, or by Hymes, or occasional works of others for reference. If a body of work is critiqued by Hymes in a correspondence, then it is contained within the file. For easier access, letters, previously filed by subject, are now filed by correspondent.
  Since Hymes edited many works, many files contain cover copies to the principals involved in the work. Some files are topical, such as Margaret Mead, which includes correspondence with her but also newspaper clippings and related material.
  The letters of invitation, sampled at every fifth letter, show acceptances in Hymes early career (1950s, 1960s) with more declinations in his days as Dean (1977-1987). The reprints, also sampled at every fifth letter, are divided into requests by others (for Hymes' work) and request by Hymes (of others' works), which includes unsolicited gifts of books and articles. Of particular note, the consultation correspondence is advice given by Hymes to students and colleagues in various areas of linguistic studies.
  Note: Hymes' responses are often carbon-copied onto the back of the original letter or onto scrap paper. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent name, then chronological.
  - Aarsleff, Hans, 1970,1971
  - Abbou, Andre, 1980-1983
  - Abel, Marianne, 1975-1977
  - Aberle, David F., 1963-1964,1968,1970
  - Abrahams, Roger, 1986
  - Academic Press, Inc., 1972,1978-1980,1985
  - Akhmanova, Olga, 1964-1968
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1969-1971
  - Alfred, Braxton M., 1964
  - Alford, Danny Keith Hawkmoon, 1978-1981
  - Allen, Irving, 1981-1982
  - Aman, Reinhold, 1973-1982
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1982
  - American Anthropologist, 1974-1975
  - American Antiquity, n.d.
  - American Association of University Professors--Berkeley Chapter, 1964
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1955,1965-1969
  - American Educational Research Association, 1983
  - American Indian Culture and Research Journal, 1980-1981
  - American Indian Historical Society, 1974
  - American Indian Quarterly, 1985
  - American Journal of Sociology, 1976-1979,1984
  - American Philosophical Society, 1955-1976,1984-1985
  - American Sociological Association, 1965-1966,1982-1983
  - American Sociological Review, 1978
  - Anales de Antropologia, 1967-1968
  - Anderson, Gene, 1967,1970
  - Andresen, Julie, 1979
  - Anthropologists for Radical Political Action, 1972
  - Anthropology and Education Quarterly, 1977
  - Aoki, Haruo, 1980
  - Appell, George N., 1968,1970-1972,1980
  - Apte, Mahadeo L. (Mahadev), 1971,1984-1985
  - Arndt, Horst, 1980-1982
  - Arvizu, Steven F., 1978-1985
  - Ascher, Robert, 1962-1964
  - Atkinson, Paul, 1984-1987
  - Austerlitz, Robert, 1965,1972,1974,1982
  - Bailey, Charles-James, 1969-1973
  - Barth, Fredrik, 1970
  - Bascom, William, 1975
  - Basil Blackwell Ltd., 1979,1985-1986
  - Basso, Ellen, 1973-1986
  - Basso, Keith, 1969-1986
  - Baugh, John, 1978-1985
  - Bauman, Richard, 1968,1971-1982,1987
  - Beatty, John, 1972
  - Becker, Howard S., 1968,1983
  - Beeman, Bill, 1982,1987
  - Behavioral & Brain Science, 1981-1982
  - Ben-Amos, Dan, 1973-1974,1980-1986
  - Bennett, Ruth S., 1978-1985
  - Berckmans, Paul, 1982-1983
  - Berg, Ivar, 1982
  - Berger, Peter, 1966-1967
  - Berlin, Brent, 1966-1967
  - Berman, Herman, 1981-1983
  - Bernstein, Basil, 1961-1973,1979-1987
  - Berntsen, Maxine, 1967-1973
  - Berreman, Gerald, 1968-1971
  - Berruecos, Maria Paz, 1983
  - Berruto, Gaetano, 1978-1979
  - Bershady, Harold J., 1973-1974
  - Bharati, A., 1965
  - Bickerton, Derek, 1973
  - Bidney, David, 1954
  - Bidwell, Charles, 1979-1983
  - Bigelow, Charles, 1972-1985; 2 folders
    See also Holmes, Kris
    - Folder 1, 1972-1976
    - Folder 2, 1977-1985
  - Bird, Charles S., 1975
  - Birdwhistell, Ray, 1965,1967,1981
  - Bittle, William E., 1963-1966
  - Black, Mary B., 1964-1977
  - Blakely, Thomas D., 1980
  - Blaker, Margaret, 1968,1982-1983
  - Bloch, Bernard, 1961,1965
  - Bloomfield, Morton, 1972,1977
  - Blount, Ben, 1972-1985
  - Blumenthal, Tanya, 1962-1965
  - Bock, Philip, 1971,1975,1982-86
  - Boeck, George, 1981
  - Bogen, James, 1978
  - Boisson, Claude, 1983
  - Bolinger, Dwight, 1968,1973,1975
  - Books on Demand, 1979-1980
  - Borko, Harold, 1961-1962
  - Bouchard, Randy, 1983
  - Boynton, David, 1982-1984
  - Boynton, Mia, 1980-1982
  - Brady, Ivan, 1983
  - Branstetter, Katherine B., 1975
  - Brant, Charles S., 1968
  - Brenneis, Donald, 1983
  - Bricker, Victoria, 1974,1982-83
  - Briggs, Charles, 1980-1986
  - Bright, William, 1961-1987; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1961-1981
    - Folder 2, 1982-1987
  - British Columbia Indian Language Project, 1982
  - Broce, Gerald, 1986
  - Bromberg, Joann, 1973-1975
  - Brooks, Robin, 1982
  - Brown, Roger, 1962-1968
  - Brudner, Lilyan, 1970-1975
  - Buchler, Ira, 1963-1966
  - Bugarski, Ranko, 1980-1981
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1968-1969
  - Bunker-Ramo Corporation, 1966-1969
  - Burke, Kenneth, 1953-1981; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1953-1969
    - Folder 2, 1970-1977
    - Folder 3, 1978-1981
  - Bursill-Hall, Geoffrey, 1961-1972
  - Buscher, Gertrud, 1967-1970
  - Byron, Janet, 1971-1974
  - CBS International Publishing, 1978
  - Cambridge University, 1965-1969
  - Cambridge University Press, 1969-1987; 5 folders
    See also Series V: Language in Society
    - Folder 1, 1969-1976
    - Folder 2, 1977-1983
    - Folder 3, 1984
    - Folder 4, 1985
    - Folder 5, 1986-1987
  - Campbell, Lyle, 1974
  - Canada Council, 1970-1973
  - Canadian Journal of Anthropology, 1982
  - Cardona, George, 1973-1986
  - Casagrande, Joseph, 1966
  - Casey, Patrick, 1980-1981
  - Casson, Ron, 1970,1974
  - Caulfield, Mina, 1970
  - Cazden, Courtney, 1965-1987, n.d.; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1965-1972
    - Folder 2, 1973-1987, n.d.
  - Ceccato, Silvio, 1962-1964
  - Center for Applied Linguistics, 1964,1966
  - Chalfen, Richard, 1982
  - Chalmer, Ann, 1975-1976
  - Chao, Y. R., 1965-66
  - Chapple, Eliot, 1966-1967
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1974-1975
  - Cicourel, Aaron, 1969-1971
  - Cleland, Ralph E., 1955
  - Clemmer, Richard O., 1969-1973
  - Cofer, Tom, 1969-1972
  - Colby, Benjamin N. (Nick), 1962-1965
  - Cole, Michael, 1976-1984
  - Columbia University Press, 1973-1979
  - Columbia University Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 1985
  - Conklin, Harold, 1956-1977
  - Consultation-by Colleagues, 1955-1987, n.d.; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1977
    - Folder 2, 1978-1987, n.d.
  - Consultation-by Students, 1961-1986, n.d.
  - Contini-Morava, Ellen, 1983-1984
  - Cook, J. A., 1965-1970, n.d.
  - Cooper, Lee, 1969-1971
  - Cornell University Press, 1975-1980
  - Corson, David, 1984-1986
  - Coulmas, Florian, 1978-1979,1986
  - Council on International Communications, 1969-1983
  - Cowgill, George L., 1963-1964
  - Crabb, David, 1967,1970,1975
    See also Tax, Sol
  - Critical Anthropology, 1970-1972
  - Current Anthropology, 1965-1974,1978
  - Current Trends in Linguistics, 1967-1973; 2 folders
    See also Sebeok, Thomas
    - Folder 1, 1967-1970
    - Folder 2, 1971-1973
  - Currie, Haver, 1972-1979
  - Currier, Richard, 1965,1971-75
  - Danes, Frantisek, 1969
  - Daedalus, 1958,1960,1970-1973
  - Dauer, Sheila, 1982-1984
  - Davidowitz, Gilbert, 1970-1973
  - Davidson, Lee, 1969
  - Davis, Boyd, 1978-1983
  - D'Azevedo, Warren L., 1965
  - DeCamp, David, 1967-1975
  - De Chene, Brent, 1979
  - DeNatale, Douglas, 1983
  - Department of Health, Education, & Welfare-Blacklist issue, 1969-1970
  - Derwing, Bruce, 1978-1981
  - Deutscher, Irwin, 1967
  - Diamond, Stanley, 1964-1965,1970-1983
  - Dickey, William Hobart, 1951-1953
  - Diebold, A. Richard, 1960-1967
  - Dil, Anwar, 1970-1971,1981
  - Dillard, Joe, 1967,1970
  - Dillon, J. T., 1980-1982
  - Dinneen, Francis P., 1971
  - Di Pietro, Robert, 1971
  - Dirven, Rene, 1981
  - Discourse Processes, 1975,1977
  - Dittmar, Norbert, 1981-1985
  - Dixon, Robert, 1963-1964
  - Dorian, Nancy, 1974-1980
  - Dorsey Press, 1970
  - Dorson, Richard M., 1966,1972
  - Douglas, Mary, 1980
  - Dozier, Edward, 1962-1963
  - Draft Counseling Board, [1967]
  - Drechsel, Emanuel, 1974,1986
  - Driver, Harold, 1956-1966,1970-1973
  - Dumont, Jean-Paul, 1975-1976
  - Dundes, Alan, 1965-1972,1977
  - Duranti, Alessandro, 1980-1985
  - Durbin, Marshall, 1968-1981
  - Duxbury Press, 1980
  - Dwyer-Shick, Susan, 1979-1981, n.d.
  - Dyen, Isidore, 1964,1970
  - Dyk, Walter, 1954-1956
  - Dyson, Robert H., 1980-1982
  - Ebert, Robert Peter, 1981-1982
  - Educational Testing Service, 1969
  - Eggan, Fred, 1963, n.d.
  - Ehrlich, Thomas, 1983, n.d.
  - Ellefson, John, 1964
  - Ellis, John M., 1977
  - Elmendorf, William, 1961-1965
  - Embree, Lester, 1980-1982
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1961,1965,1967
  - Enrico, John, 1981,1985-1986
  - Epstein, Stephen M., 1978
  - Ethnohistory, 1983,1985
  - Fabian, Johannes, 1970-1984
  - Faerch, Claus, 1985-1986
  - Fanselow, John, 1978
  - Farb, Peter, 1968-1969
  - Faris, James, 1967,1970
  - Farrer, Claire R., 1974-1981
  - Fasold, Ralph W., 1973
  - Feld, Steve, 1975-1985
  - Fergsuon, Charles A., 1981,1984
  - Fernandez, Jim, 1966,1985
  - Fernando, Chitra, 1983
  - Fiering, Sue, 1979
  - Figueroa, John J., 1968,1970-1972
  - Fillmore, Charles J., 1981
  - Finlayson, Rosalie, 1981
  - Fischer, John L. (Jack), 1960-1975
  - Fishman, Joshua A., 1968-1986
  - Fitzgerald, Dale, 1970-1971
  - Flavell, John H., 1963
  - Flood, Cynthia, 1983
  - Fluehr-Lobban, Carolyn, 1981
  - Foerstel, Lenora, 1981,1986
  - Fogelson, Raymond D., 1975
  - Fonagy, Ivan, 1965,1976
  - Fontana, Bernard, 1970,1972
  - Ford, Richard, 1983
  - Forman, Sylvia, 1967-1975,1985
  - Fortes, Meyer, 1968-1969
  - Foster, Mary LeCron, 1975-1976
  - Foster, Michael K., 1968-1981, 1986
    - Folder 1, 1968-1970
    - Folder 2, 1971-1981, 1986
  - Fought, John, 1973,1977-1986, n.d.
  - Foundations of Language, 1966-1967,1976-1977
  - Fox, Renee C., 1972-1977
  - Fox, Robin, 1966-1968
  - Frader, Joel, 1977
  - Frake, Charles O., 1960-1986